Kelly Zhang

Senior Machine Learning Engineer

golive.future@gmail.com | +17856694192 | New York, New York, USA https://www.linkedin.com/in/kelly-zhang-930752246/

PROFILE

Passionate and Hard working Machine Learning Engineer with relevant skills and experiences in Data Engineering and Data Science. I have provided excellent suggestions and solutions to the companies so that they have touched over \$13M.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree / Computer Science, *University of Pittsburgh*

08/2008 - 08/2012

- Won the 1st place in programming competition
- Explored various aspects of artificial intelligence, including knowledge representation, reasoning, planning, and expert systems.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Machine Learning Engineer, *KiwiTech*

05/2018 - 05/2023

- New York, USA
- Expertized in establishing MLOps pipeline for projects and ML algorithms including regression, classification, clustering
- Professionally experienced with AWS Lambda, Sagemaker, Kinesis, Firehose, Glue, Athena, EKS, EMR, Redshift, CodeBuild, CodeCommit and led as a technical advisor
- Mentor and guide junior team members, provide technical leadership, and contribute to knowledge sharing initiatives.

• Preprocess and analyze complex data sets to extract meaningful features and insights.

Machine Learning Engineer, Guardian Life Insurance Limited

08/2016 - 05/2018 New York, USA

- Implemented Cloud based 10+ Machine Learning projects with the combination of coding, relational database, MySQL, Oracle, Computer Science NLP and data-driven projects such as AI Poster, CRM and Recommendation System
- Completed 10+ Deep Learning based computer vision, NLP projects using frameworks such as Tensorflow, PyTorch, Yolo Model and successfully deployed 5+ large-scale production AI solutions.
- · Work closely with software engineers to integrate machine learning algorithms into software applications.

Machine Learning Intern, Federal Reserve Board of Governors

08/2014 - 08/2016 Washington DC, USA

- Collected and analyzed data from news and social media sources, and developed 12+ predictive models for cryptocurrency futures trading.
- Designed Natural Language Processing (NLP) algorithms to valuate cryptocurrencies using sentiment analysis (Python, NLTK) and improved accuracy up to 96%.
- Provided analytical support for the launch and management of new quantitative investment for 8 products & strategies.

Full-stack Developer, Niji

• Developed 10+ new application features and distributed services that support high-scale Canton of Cesson, France applications

- Created Web Application that allowed 75k users to search for nearby hotels and restaurants based on their location with 97% accuracy.
- Worked with a team of 30 developers that created several e-commerce websites using PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, React, Vue, Angular and so on within 8 months

SKILLS

Machine Learning (Python, AWS, GCP, Azure, Keras, Numpy, Scikit-Learn, CI/CD, ChatGPT, GPT4, Stable Diffusion, LLM, Computer Vision, NLP, Docker, Kubernetes, LSTM, CNN, RNN, Spacy)

Full Stack Development (React.js, Angular.js, Node.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, ASP.NET, Flask, PHP, Django, RESTful API, SQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL)

Programming (Python, C++, C#, Java, JavaScript, R, Scala, Delphi)

09/2012 - 08/2014